Phil Vigus

Software Developer

□ philvigus@gmail.com

www.philvigus.com

in www.linkedin.com/in/philvigus

github.com/PhilipVigus

PROFILE

After qualifying with a degree in Computer Science, I spent much of my career working in technology and education. A few years ago I completed the Maker's Academy coding bootcamp before becoming Software Developer at Mumsnet. I recently moved to Stockholm where I now work as a Backend Consultant specialising in Java and JavaScript with AWS.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages - Java, JavaScript/TypeScript, PHP Frameworks and libraries - Spring Boot, Hibernate, Serverless Framework, Laravel, Livewire, React

Databases - SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB, Redis, MongoDB

Dev-Ops/CI/CD - AWS, Terraform, Github Actions, Docker, Heroku, DigitalOcean

Docker, Heroku, Digitalocean

Other - Testing/TDD, Git, Agile/Scrum, OOP, RESTful APIs

CERTIFICATES

AWS Associate Solutions Architect ☑ 2022

PROJECTS

Database entity factories 🛮

Allows you to easily create and persist entities with random but logical attributes using Spring Boot and Hibernate.

Film follower 🗷

Designed to help shortlist films to watch. Written using Tailwind, Alpine, Laravel and Livewire.

KEY PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Backend Developer/Consultant, *Devoteam* ☑

09/2022 - present | Stockholm, Sweden

- Completing the migration of a client's key application from using MySQL to a MongoDB database
- Maintaining a complex legacy codebase utilising AWS (Lambda, Step Functions, SQS, SNS, API Gateway, CloudFormation etc) and integrations with a large number of external systems
- Building an IoT project to control the air quality in meeting rooms
- Supporting business development by providing technical input to bid documents and estimates

Backend Java Developer, *The Climate App* □

10/2022 - present | Remote

- Lead developer on the administration and user management system
- Implementing new features and maintaining the main application backend

Developer, Mumsnet

11/2020 - 08/2022 | London, UK

- Writing and optimising scripts to migrate large amounts of data from a legacy database, reducing runtime from five days to three hours
- Implementing a new CMS, reducing the time taken to create an article from two hours to half an hour
- Developing the main talk forum and admin system
- Mentoring and onboarding new team members

SOFT SKILLS

Communication

Working in multi-disciplinary teams and clientfacing roles at Devoteam, Mumsnet and OCN London.

Problem solving

Designing and implementing features at Devoteam and Mumsnet, working with assistive technology at The National Star College.

High emotional intelligence

Mentoring, pair programming and doing code reviews at Mumsnet, and empathising with diverse clients at OCN London and Aspire.

ADDITIONAL PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS

Welfare Benefits Administrator, Aspire

02/2018 - 07/2018

- First point of contact for often distressed clients, using empathy to help them understand available and appropriate services
- Communicating across multi-disciplinary teams to ensure work with clients was consistent

Senior Administration Officer then Quality Reviewer, *OCNLR*

04/2007 - 10/2012

- Managing a caseload of 150+ educational centres across London, using strong interpersonal skills to develop relationships with clients and grow their business
- Working with centres to improve their quality utilising strong problem-solving skills to identify and resolve issues
- Writing detailed reports and handling complex queries using excellent communication skills
- Delivering training to colleagues and clients using teamwork and high levels of empathy

IT Access Technical Developer and ICT Teacher,

The National Star College

09/2004 - 11/2006

- Evaluating and solving problems with learners' assistive technology needs, and training them to use their equipment
- Training staff and teaching students using my technical knowledge and understanding of how people learn

Research Scientist, QinetiQ

07/2000 - 08/2003

Building computer simulations using my problem-solving and technical skills

Software Developer, Quidnunc

07/1999 - 01/2000

• Building e-commerce websites

EDUCATION

Software Development, *Maker's Academy*

2020

A 16-week intensive programming bootcamp

PGCE (ICT), Exeter University

2004

A postgraduate certificate in education, specialising in Information and Communication Technologies

BSc. (Hons) Computer Science (2:1),

The University of Nottingham 1996 – 1999

LANGUAGES

English (native speaker)

Swedish (beginner)

Evening classes at City of Westminster University